[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So as we use our data visualization tools to visualize databases,
当我们用数据可视化工具 来可视化数据库
to visualize data cubes, these data cubes are data hypercubes.
和数据立方时 这些数据立方就是数据超立方
They're going to be high-dimensional databases with lots of dimensions.
它们是高维数据库 有非常多维度
Our challenge is going to be getting that information presented on
其挑战性在于 如何将信息
a two-dimensional screen.
显示在二维平面上
And as we've seen before, we can use worlds within worlds.
正如前文 我们可以用 大世界中的小世界
In this case, we're visualizing a four-dimensional hypercube
本例中我们将可视化一个 四维的超立方
of our World Bank indicator data.
数据是我们的世界银行指数
We're looking at life expectancy versus infant mortality, but
我们观察的不仅是 预期寿命和婴儿死亡率对比
we're also looking at that over different regions and also over different years.
还会看到它们在不同地区和 不同年份的变化
And so we have this worlds within worlds.
这样就有了大世界中的小世界
We're looking at a four-dimensional hypercube where we're plotting a table
我们看的是一个四维超立方 这里画了一张表
of region versus year, and each element in that table is,
坐标分别是年度和地区 表中的每个元素本身
itself, a two-dimensional plot of life expectancy versus infant mortality.
都是一个预期寿命和婴儿死亡率 的二维图标
So this gives us a four-dimensional view that we can expand from just that worlds
这就给了我们一个四维的视图 我们可以从这个
within worlds idea to the general idea of the organization of these axes.
世界套世界的想法扩展到 范围更广的坐标轴安排上
And each of these axes is representing different dimensions of our data.
每个坐标轴表示数据 的不同维度
And the relationship of the dimensions of our data is organized quite well
各维度的关系
in OLAP databases as the relationship between keys.
在OLAP数据库中通过关键词有效地组织起来
So these database visualization systems
这些数据库可视化系统
have special tools designed to help organize axes,
有专门设计的工具 来帮助安排坐标轴
especially since those axes are often used to display multiple dimensions or
尤其是坐标轴常常 被用于显示多个维度
represent different aggregations or projections of multiple dimensions
或者表示不同聚合 或者多维度投影
in order to reduce the dimensionality of a large hypercube.
这是为了减少较大 超立方的维度
And these are rows from a paper on Polaris.
这些数据行来自关于Polaris的一篇论文
Polaris is an early prototype system that was a precursor to Tableau.
Polaris是一个早期原型系统 是Tableau的前身
So one of the things you can do with axes is concatenate them.
你可以把坐标轴连接起来
You can take two dimensions and
可以将两个维度
place one dimension after the other in order to display that on a single axis.
把一个放在另一个后面 这样可以在一单轴上显示
And it provides, basically, multiple views of the data.
基本上这就为数据提供了 多个视图
For example, here's our sales data plotted by quarter.
例如 这是我们根据季度 画出的销售数据
And so you can see that the sales were low in the first two quarters and
可以看到在前二季度 销售量较低
then they increased in the second two quarters.
然后在三四季度上涨
And so we can concatenate the time dimension
这样我们可以把 时间维度和产品维度
with the product dimension into a single axis that has time followed by product.
产品跟在时间的后面
And so we're getting two views of the same data, but in the first half of the axis
这样我们就对同一份数据 有两个视图 但在前一半里面
we're seeing the data plotted over time, separated by quarter.
我们看到的是相对于时间的数据 根据季度划分
And in the second half of the axis we're seeing the same data plotted but
而在后一半里我们看到的是 用同样的数据画的图
separated by product.
却根据产品区分
And so we can see that this general trend of sales over time
可以看出销量在时间上 的总体趋势
is being followed by the three different products, but it's
以及之后的三个 不同产品(的销量趋势)
more accentuated with one of the products than it is perhaps with the other two.
但也许这更着重于单个产品 而不是其他两个产品
And so
因此
that makes sense to concatenate a time axis with a product axis in this case.
本例中把时间轴和产品轴 连接起来还比较顺理
It may not make sense to concatenate a quarter axis with
把季度轴和月度轴 连起来可能就说不通
a month axis because they're both time dimensions, and
因为它们都是时间维度
so you'd be seeing the same plot here over the demarcations of quarter and
这样会在季度分界线前 以及月度分界线前
then the same plot over the demarcations of a month.
看到相同的数据图
And you'd be using half of the space to build this up, and
而你为此多增加了一半空间
so it doesn't make as much sense in that case.
而结果不太合理
We can also take two dimensions and
我们也可以选择两个维度
create an axis from the product of those two dimensions.
然后根据这两个维度的某种组合 创建一个坐标轴
For example, if we have the data over time, over four quarters.
例如 如果我有相对时间的数据 如跨越四个季度
And we have the data over products instead of showing them side-by-side,
我们有关于产品的数据 那我们可以把咖啡 浓缩咖啡
we might show the data for the coffee, espresso and tea, the product values for
和茶的产品数据按一季度 二季度 三季度 四季度来显示
quarter one, quarter two, quarter three, quarter four.
而非把按产品类型划分 的数据排到一起
And so this product basically gives you every combination of coffee and
这样得到的结果可以给你 每种咖啡和季度组合的数据
quarter so that you can see how your data's performing over time and
这样就能看到数据随着时间 和产品类型的表现
product simultaneously, with a single axis here representing these two
用一条轴就可以 表示两个维度的数据
dimensions by looking at all the combinations.
一眼看到所有组合
Similarly, we could look at quarter times month.
与之相似 我们也可以 来看季度与月份组合的图表
This doesn't make much sense either, because we'd be looking at the first
但这同样没什么意义 因为我们 要看的是第一季度
quarter, which should represent just the first three months and yet
它应该只表示前三个月
I'm plotting all 12 months here.
但这里我画了 所有的十二个月
And so just doing a simple product of two time axes doesn't really
所以如果只是将同一产品属性 在两个时间轴展现 并无意义
help, because I'd only have data for the first quarter showing up in
因为这样我就只有 第一季度的数据显示了
the first three months, and then the other nine months would basically be
前三个月 而余下九个月 的值则为零
zero valued because there wouldn't be data for these months.
因为没有这几个月的数据
That was also in the first quarter.
对于第一季度来说也是如此
What makes sense for this case is to do something called nesting, and
对本例来说 有用的是 使用嵌套的方法
nesting is a way of limiting the combinations
嵌套是一种把组合限制在
to the combinations that are available in the database.
只有数据库中能找到 的组合的范围里
And so in quarter one maybe we didn't have any sales of tea.
所以在第一季度我们可能 没有茶的销量
In quarter three maybe we didn't have any sales of espresso.
在第三季度没有 浓缩咖啡的销量
And so by doing this nesting operation, it's basically similar
使用这种嵌套操作 类似于进行单一属性的组合
to a product except we're not looking at every possible combination.
但无需放入所有可能的组合
We're only showing on the axes the combinations that actually exist in
在轴上只是显示在数据库中
the database.
存在的组合的数据
And so now, if we have the month nested inside quarter,
那么如果我们把月份 嵌套到季度里面
if you have quarter as the major axis.
如果你用季度作为主轴
And then the minor axis is the month.
月份作为次轴
We're not seeing January, February, March, April, May, June all in quarter one.
那么在第一季度里 我们不是看到一月到六月所有的月份
We're only seeing the months in quarter one where we have actual
而只是看到第一季度里 在数据库中有实际数据的
data values in the database.
月份
And since January, February, March are the three months in quarter one,
因为第一季度有 一 二 三 共三个月份
we'll have data values there, but we wouldn't for April, May and June.
我们在这三个月有数据 但四五六月没有
We won't have any data values for April, May and June in quarter one because April,
那么我们在第一季度的 四五六月没有数据
May and June are in quarter two.
因为四五六月属于第二季度
And so that nicely nests this higher resolution time
这样就把细分的时间轴 嵌入了粗分的时间轴
axis into this coarser resolution time axis, into a single axis.
形成单一的轴
So Tableau has some functionality that helps organize axes nicely.
Tableau有一些功能 可以帮助我们很好地安排轴
If we take our life expectancy data and display that,
如果选择预期寿命数据来显示
we get an average over all time over all the countries.
就会得到所有国家 关于时间的平均值
And so we can start to disaggregate this data by country.
我们可以对数据根据国家来去聚合
And what we will get is an alphabetized list of all the countries.
我们可以得到一个 按国家字母排序的列表
If we want to organize this better, we can organize it by the continents.
如果想要排得更好些 可以按大洲排列
And now we get continents on the top and
这样就把大洲显示在顶部
then all the countries alphabetized by the continents.
洲内各国按字母顺序排列
And then we can insert a subregion in here that further refines the data
然后可以在这里插入一个子区域
by subregion.
对数据按子区域进一步细分
So you get this nice organization that Tableau can automatically discover
这就得到这样一个非常好的排布 Tableau可以基于这里的数据自动排列
based on the data that's in there because the data's in there by country,
因为这里的数据是按国家
by region and by subregion.
按区域和按子区域来划分的
And it can detect how that data should be
它也可以探测数据应该如何
organized hierarchically in the axis by each one of these sections.
根据每个区域在轴上划分层级
So it's by region, then subregion, then country and region, and
也就是先根据区域 然后子区域 然后是国家和地区
so we've got Africa and Eastern Africa, and
我们这里有非洲和东非
then we have all the countries alphabetically in Eastern Africa.
以及按字母顺序排列的 东非的所有国家
We can further subdivide this axis.
我们还可以把轴再细分
For example, if we want to disaggregate by the year,
例如 如果要按年份去聚合
each one of these bars represents the average over a year.
这里每个柱体表示 一年的平均值
If we want to drill down into how the performance is over each year,
如果我们要下钻到 年度的表现数据
I can add for each country the performance over each year.
我可以加上每个国家 按每个年度的数据
And now for each country, I've got the performance per year.
这样对每个国家 就有了其年度的表现数据
And this might look better actually as a line graph so
这如果换成折线图 可能会看起来更好
that we can see how each country's improving its performance in life
这样就可以看到每个国家
expectancy over the 11 years that we've recorded it here.
在过去11年里 如何提升预期寿命 记录都在这里
You can also move the year in between, and so
你也可以把年度移到中间
now we're seeing the performance on a per region basis.
这样就看到基于 每个区域的表现
This is how each of the countries in a given region are performing over a year.
这就是某个区域内每个国家 在一年中的表现情况
And then finally, you can move year all the way out and
最后你还可以把年度整个移走
now we're seeing for each year the different breakdown in the countries.
现在我们看的就是每年中 按国家的不同细分
And so you can set up these hierarchical axes and get worlds within worlds.
这样可以设置轴的层级关系 得到这种嵌套的结果
You could even put it on the vertical axis and you can get a higher dimensional view
你甚至可以把它放到垂直轴上 得到数据的高维视图
of your data by basically implementing a worlds within worlds visualization.
即通过实现一种 世界嵌套世界的可视化
Where you have a table of plots and
这里你有以表格呈现的 一系列图表
each cell of a two-dimensional data is itself a two-dimensional plot, or
而且每个二维数据的元素本身 是一个二维图
two-dimensional table, or in this case, a two-dimensional bar chart.
或者一个二维表格 或者本例中的二维柱状图
So we can see how information visualization systems specifically
我们由此看到信息可视化系统 为数据库可视化
designed for visualizing databases,
而专门设计
specifically OLAP data cube style databases, can provide
尤其是针对OLAP数据立方 样式的数据库
a database user with visualization tools to gain insight into the data.
同时也为数据库用户提供了 可视化的工具以对数据进行深入探究
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community